<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<event category="CREATE" id="0">
  <actions>
    <action id="603" library="1">
      <!--action name: Code-->
      <kind>CODE</kind>
      <allowRelative>false</allowRelative>
      <question>false</question>
      <canApplyTo>true</canApplyTo>
      <actionType>CODE</actionType>
      <functionName/>
      <relative>false</relative>
      <not>false</not>
      <appliesTo>.self</appliesTo>
      <arguments>
        <argument kind="STRING">//Enclosing a part of a message in square brackets [] will cause the 
//enclosed string to be highlighted.

//Placing an asterisk * at the end of a message tells the code that
//the current message is the last message.

//Putting an exponent sign ^ at the end of a message followed by a number will cause the 
//next position to be at the number. If it is followed by a number, a comma, and then another number,
//then the code will open up a box for the player to choose which path to take.
//The first number is for the yes position, and the second is for the no position.

//If you surround a number by a less than sign &lt; and a greater then sign &gt;, the code will do a manual
//pause for the  specified number of steps.

//These are the actual messages.
str[0] = "What?! [Tex] and [Crazy Lu?!] What are you doing here?!"
str[1] = "[ARS] has come to reclaim the [Bot Blueprints.] We knew you would try to beat us to it. [ARS,] i.e. the [Anti-Refrigerator Society,] was founded by [Gertrude] to unite all of the apples in taking down the refrigerators."
str[2] = "You and your friends are no different from the refrigerators, for you are traitors and deserve to be executed. We always succeed in solving problems, and you are no different a problem than the refrigerators."
str[3] = "AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAHHHH!!!"
str[4] = "[Evil Toaster?!]"
str[5] = "What?! So this is the freak you've been fighting all along?! The [Evil Refrigerator] was much tougher than this, and [ARS] still managed to destroy her, although [Numera] took her place as the new [Evil Refrigerator.]"
str[6] = "AHH! This brown apple here is the same guy who made me run away and steal the [Worminator] in order to travel to the future!"
str[7] = "So this blue thing here, the [Worminator,] allows time travel? That gives me an idea! I shall travel back in time and kill [App,] causing him to stop existing in present time!"
str[8] = "Hey! Killing [the Apple] is MY job!"
str[9] = "You seem like too much of a coward to kill someone like [App.] And that's saying something, because I bet I could defeat a younger [App] without using a gun. Come on, [Crazy Lu,] let's go!"
str[10] = "... &lt;30&gt;So, [apple,] &lt;10&gt;I mean, [App...] &lt;20&gt;You have a face now?!"
str[11] = "The other apples and I have evolved."
str[12] = "Where are the other apples right now?"
str[13] = "[Leaf] is currently hanging out with his girlfriend, [Soap] is nearby, [Mach] is also nearby, [Shaman] is busy doing something important and secret, and [Elemna] went on some galactic adventure thing."
str[14] = "Who is [Mach?]"
str[15] = "Mach is a new apple that arrived just a week ago. He's intelligent with electronics. I'm not sure where all of the new apples come from. All I know is that they just randomly appear on [Planet Stone] with no recollection on how they got here."
str[16] = "Why are you willingly giving me all of this information?"
str[17] = "You are no longer part of my problems."
str[18] = "What?!"
str[19] = "[Roaster] has replaced you as the new [Evil Toaster.]"
str[20] = "Eh?! No! NOO! I'M REPLACED! I'M USELESS! NOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOO!!!"
str[21] = "It's strange to think that the [Evil Toaster] was once my dangerous arch-rival, but now he's been reduced to an extreme wimp..."
str[22] = "Darn, I wasn't even able to defeat a young [App.] I bet I would've won if I brought a gun, though..."
str[23] = "Did you really bring a thingy called a [Power Box] with you?"
str[24] = "I lied about taking a [Power Box.] According to the [Bot Blueprints,] a [Power Box] is a power component that's attached to every [Bot.] I don't know what would actually happen if I tried attaching a [Power Box] to myself."
str[25] = "So a [Bot] would die if its [Power Box] got destroyed, right?"
str[26] = "Yes. However, [Power Boxes] sound very difficult to destroy, and each [Bot] is nowhere near stupid enough to let an enemy get near their [Power Box.] Why do you ask?"
str[27] = "Well, you never know if you might need to fight a [Bot] in the near future..."
str[28] = "Pfft! Fighting a [Bot?!] What an absurd concept! No apple has ever seen a [Bot] in person! Anyways, where did the [Evil Toaster] go?"
str[29] = "The [Evil Toaster] ran away because he was horrified that [Roaster] replaced him as the new [Evil Toaster...] Oh yeah, [Roaster] is that black flying toaster, in case you didn't know."
str[30] = "Huh. [Numera] replaced the [Evil Refrigerator] as well. I suppose both of our groups have similar roots."
str[31] = "WHY ARE YOU HAVING SUCH A PEACEFUL CONVERSATION?!"
str[32] = "I've begun to envy [App.]"
str[33] = "Eheh... Thanks. But why are you still fighting my friends and I?"
str[34] = "It doesn't matter who I fight. I just want to defeat opponents and become stronger."
str[35] = "That's bold, but it's not very nice towards your opponents, or, in this case, me and the other apples from the other side of the [Great Stone Wall.]"
str[36] = "Well, fighting isn't nice in general."
str[37] = "I agree. Couldn't you and the rest of [ARS] just stop fighting and become allies with my friends and I?"
str[38] = "I would if I could, but [Gertrude] is the leader of [ARS.] Being the furious girl she is, she doesn't want to stop fighting until she gets sweet revenge after you and your friends broke through the [Great Stone Wall.]"
str[39] = "Can't you rebel against her or something?"
str[40] = "Listen, [App.] I suppose I can let you pass here without any further trouble. It's the most I can do. I dunno about [Crazy Lu,] though... Good luck."
str[41] = "Thanks, [Tex.]*"
//These are the headshots that correspond to each message.
img[0] = AppFace
img[1] = TexFace
img[2] = TexFace
img[3] = ToasterChipA
img[4] = AppFace
img[5] = TexFace
img[6] = ToasterChipA
img[7] = TexFace
img[8] = ToasterChipA
img[9] = TexFace
img[10] = ToasterChipA
img[11] = AppFace
img[12] = ToasterChipA
img[13] = AppFace
img[14] = ToasterChipA
img[15] = AppFace
img[16] = ToasterChipA
img[17] = AppFace
img[18] = ToasterChipA
img[19] = AppFace
img[20] = ToasterChipA
img[21] = AppFace
img[22] = TexFace
img[23] = AppFace
img[24] = TexFace
img[25] = AppFace
img[26] = TexFace
img[27] = AppFace
img[28] = TexFace
img[29] = AppFace
img[30] = TexFace
img[31] = CLFace
img[32] = TexFace
img[33] = AppFace
img[34] = TexFace
img[35] = AppFace
img[36] = TexFace
img[37] = AppFace
img[38] = TexFace
img[39] = AppFace
img[40] = TexFace
img[41] = AppFace
//These are the names of the person talking in each message.
name[0] = "App"
name[1] = "Tex"
name[2] = "Tex"
name[3] = "Evil Toaster"
name[4] = "App"
name[5] = "Tex"
name[6] = "Evil Toaster"
name[7] = "Tex"
name[8] = "Evil Toaster"
name[9] = "Tex"
name[10] = "Evil Toaster"
name[11] = "App"
name[12] = "Evil Toaster"
name[13] = "App"
name[14] = "Evil Toaster"
name[15] = "App"
name[16] = "Evil Toaster"
name[17] = "App"
name[18] = "Evil Toaster"
name[19] = "App"
name[20] = "Evil Toaster"
name[21] = "App"
name[22] = "Tex"
name[23] = "App"
name[24] = "Tex"
name[25] = "App"
name[26] = "Tex"
name[27] = "App"
name[28] = "Tex"
name[29] = "App"
name[30] = "Tex"
name[31] = "Crazy Lu"
name[32] = "Tex"
name[33] = "App"
name[34] = "Tex"
name[35] = "App"
name[36] = "Tex"
name[37] = "App"
name[38] = "Tex"
name[39] = "App"
name[40] = "Tex"
name[41] = "App"
//As you can see, it is quite easy to add extra details for
//each message simply by adding an extra array. 
//It's that simple!

//This determines the number of pixels each line can be.
line_length = 420
//This controls the speed of the the text.
text_speed = 1
//This is the  x position in which the string starts at.
string_x = 16
//This is the y position in which the string starts at.
string_y = 48
//This determines the vertical spacing between lines.
//When set to zero, the spacing will only be the string's height.
vertical_spacing = 0
//This is the x position of the question box.
question_box_x = 32
//This is the y position of the question box.
question_box_y = 128
//This is the x position of the text drawn in relevance to question_box_x.
question_x = 18
//This is the y position of the text drawn in relevance to question_box_y.
question_y = 7
//This is the x position of the names.
name_x = 50
//This is the y position of the names.
name_y = 22
//This is the x position of the headshot.
headshot_x = 12
//This is the y position of the headshot.
headshot_y = 12
//This is the vertical spacing in between "Yes" and "No".
question_vert_spacing = 2
//This is the x postion in relevance to question_box_x.
highlight_x = 2
//If this charcter is detected, initiate a highlight.
highlight_open_character = "["
//This character determines the end of a highlight. Anything enclosed
//will be highlighted.
highlight_close_character = "]"
//If this charcter is detected, end messages.
end_character = "*"
//If this charcter is detected, ask question or jump to next position.
jump_character = "^"
//If this character is detected, initiate a manual pause.
pause_open_character = "&lt;"
//This character determines the number. The enclosed number
//is the length of the manual pause.
pause_close_character = "&gt;"


//The following variables do not need to be changed and are only used
//by the code.



//This determins if the messages end.
message_end = 0
//This determines when the typing is finished.
type_end = 0
//This determines if the meesage is a question message.
message_question = 0
//This is the target position if yes is selected.
yes_position = 0
//This is the target position if no is selected.
no_position = 0
//This is the option selected by the user.
question_selection = 1
//This detemins if the message is a jump message.
message_jump = 0
//This is the position of the next message.
jump_position = 0
//This is the string that is going to be displayed. It contains the
//modified version of the actual string.
display_string = ""
//This states the current position we are at in str[x] for adding
//characters into display_string.
position = 0
//This states the current position we are in display_string. This is
//used to prevent line breaks in the middle of a word.
display_position= 0
//This counter tells us when it's time to make a line break.
width_counter = 0
//This finds the last space.
last_space = 0
//The array index of the message that is currently being displayed.
message_display = 0
//This is used to count the number of phrases that will be highlighted.
highlight_number = 0
//This stores the starting position of the highlighted text.
highlight_position[0] = 0
//This stores the length of the highlighted text.
highlight_length[0] = 0
//This is used to count the number of manual pauses that are in the message.
pause_number = 0
//This stores the position of the manual pause.
pause_position[0] = 0
//This stores the number of steps the manual pause lasts.
pause_length[0] = 0
//This variable stores the edited message.
current_string = ""


//Gives the user a second to realize the window has opened before the text
//starts typing out.
alarm[0] = 10
</argument>
      </arguments>
    </action>
    <action id="611" library="1">
      <!--action name: Variable-->
      <kind>VARIABLE</kind>
      <allowRelative>true</allowRelative>
      <question>false</question>
      <canApplyTo>true</canApplyTo>
      <actionType>CODE</actionType>
      <functionName/>
      <relative>false</relative>
      <not>false</not>
      <appliesTo>.self</appliesTo>
      <arguments>
        <argument kind="STRING">nexted</argument>
        <argument kind="EXPRESSION">0</argument>
      </arguments>
    </action>
    <action id="201" library="1">
      <!--action name: Create_Object-->
      <kind>NORMAL</kind>
      <allowRelative>true</allowRelative>
      <question>false</question>
      <canApplyTo>true</canApplyTo>
      <actionType>FUNCTION</actionType>
      <functionName>action_create_object</functionName>
      <relative>false</relative>
      <not>false</not>
      <appliesTo>.self</appliesTo>
      <arguments>
        <argument kind="GMOBJECT">Uncontrollable</argument>
        <argument kind="EXPRESSION">0</argument>
        <argument kind="EXPRESSION">0</argument>
      </arguments>
    </action>
    <action id="611" library="1">
      <!--action name: Variable-->
      <kind>VARIABLE</kind>
      <allowRelative>true</allowRelative>
      <question>false</question>
      <canApplyTo>true</canApplyTo>
      <actionType>CODE</actionType>
      <functionName/>
      <relative>false</relative>
      <not>false</not>
      <appliesTo>.self</appliesTo>
      <arguments>
        <argument kind="STRING">stage</argument>
        <argument kind="EXPRESSION">0</argument>
      </arguments>
    </action>
  </actions>
</event>
