<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<event category="CREATE" id="0">
  <actions>
    <action id="603" library="1">
      <!--action name: Code-->
      <kind>CODE</kind>
      <allowRelative>false</allowRelative>
      <question>false</question>
      <canApplyTo>true</canApplyTo>
      <actionType>CODE</actionType>
      <functionName/>
      <relative>false</relative>
      <not>false</not>
      <appliesTo>.self</appliesTo>
      <arguments>
        <argument kind="STRING">//Enclosing a part of a message in square brackets [] will cause the 
//enclosed string to be highlighted.

//Placing an asterisk * at the end of a message tells the code that
//the current message is the last message.

//Putting an exponent sign ^ at the end of a message followed by a number will cause the 
//next position to be at the number. If it is followed by a number, a comma, and then another number,
//then the code will open up a box for the player to choose which path to take.
//The first number is for the yes position, and the second is for the no position.

//If you surround a number by a less than sign &lt; and a greater then sign &gt;, the code will do a manual
//pause for the  specified number of steps.

//These are the actual messages.
str[0] = "Goodie! Now that all of the sane apples are united, we can verbalize the crap out of EVERYONE!"
str[1] = "Guns are better."
str[2] = "Are you joking?"
str[3] = "No."
str[4] = "Well, I was joking."
str[5] = "Darn."
str[6] = "So... did anyone get the [Bot Blueprints?]"
str[7] = "[Aneroid] told me he burned them in lava."
str[8] = "[Aneroid?]"
str[9] = "The red robot. He took us to [Frank's Fleet] and locked everyone except [App] in a cage. Of course, [App] arrived and rescued [Angela, Chroma,] and I, as always."
str[10] = "HE BURNED THE BLUEPRINTS? WHY?"
str[11] = "[Aneroid] told me that any more [Bots] would be a bad thing. He never told me why."
str[12] = "He's a cryptic one, isn't he?"
str[13] = "Oh well. So who's this orange apple?"
str[14] = "My name is [Chroma] and I have lived on [Frank's Fleet] for as long as I remember."
str[15] = "How old are you?"
str[16] = "I don't know. I lost track of time and I never asked [Frank.]"
str[17] = "[FRANK?!] I mean... who's [Frank?]"
str[18] = "[Mach,] do you know [Frank?]"
str[19] = "No..."
str[20] = "You're hiding something."
str[21] = "No I'm not."
str[22] = "I'll [D-Smash] you."
str[23] = "Alright, fine. I confess. I'm older than I let on."
str[24] = "Oh? Why didn't you tell us?"
str[25] = "I was afraid that you guys would treat me differently."
str[26] = "There's nothing wrong with being an old guy! You'll just die sooner than us!"
str[27] = "Ouch."
str[28] = "So you're old. And?"
str[29] = "I was created to be a prototype apple. The only apple older than me was a red apple named [Jim.] Back in the day, there were lots of glowing thingies out and about."
str[30] = "Glowing thingies? Did they have wings?"
str[31] = "Huh? How do you know of them?"
str[32] = "I went to a random tunnel in the middle of a charred place and I saw one floating in the entrance of the tunnel."
str[33] = "YOU WENT THERE?!"
str[34] = "Yeah."
str[35] = "Never go back to that place again. I swear it's haunted."
str[36] = "Alright, whatever."
str[37] = "Anyways, I hung out with [Jim] for a week before we found an entrance to the [Core.] This core entrance is the same tunnel that [App] apparently went to and could've gotten himself killed at..."
str[38] = "You're talking about that place with all the charred ground? That's the tunnel that [Gertrude] went into three years ago... She seemed scarred after that."
str[39] = "[GERTRUDE] TOO?! Geez, this planet is full of idiots."
str[40] = "Well, [Gertrude] IS an idiot, as proven by that last incident."
str[41] = "ANYWAYS, [Jim] and I entered the tunnel in hopes of hiding. Soon later, I got an eye damaged by one of those glowing things. We left the tunnel after that and [Jim] gave me a pair of infrared goggles so I could see well again."
str[42] = "Is [Jim] still alive?"
str[43] = "I don't know. After he gave me these goggles, he went back into that tunnel without me and I haven't seen him since. He's probably still inside of his cozy little fortress down underground, laughing at us... I hate him."
str[44] = "What did you do after [Jim] left?"
str[45] = "I went to live with the [Bots...]*"
//These are the headshots that correspond to each message.
img[0] = MachFace
img[1] = TexFace
img[2] = MachFace
img[3] = TexFace
img[4] = MachFace
img[5] = TexFace
img[6] = MachFace
img[7] = SoapFace
img[8] = MachFace
img[9] = SoapFace
img[10] = MachFace
img[11] = SoapFace
img[12] = AngelaFace
img[13] = MachFace
img[14] = ChromaFace
img[15] = MachFace
img[16] = ChromaFace
img[17] = MachFace
img[18] = TexFace
img[19] = MachFace
img[20] = TexFace
img[21] = MachFace
img[22] = TexFace
img[23] = MachFace
img[24] = AppFace
img[25] = MachFace
img[26] = SoapFace
img[27] = MachFace
img[28] = TexFace
img[29] = MachFace
img[30] = AppFace
img[31] = MachFace
img[32] = AppFace
img[33] = MachFace
img[34] = AppFace
img[35] = MachFace
img[36] = AppFace
img[37] = MachFace
img[38] = AngelaFace
img[39] = MachFace
img[40] = TexFace
img[41] = MachFace
img[42] = AngelaFace
img[43] = MachFace
img[44] = AppFace
img[45] = MachFace
//These are the names of the person talking in each message.
name[0] = "Mach"
name[1] = "Tex"
name[2] = "Mach"
name[3] = "Tex"
name[4] = "Mach"
name[5] = "GUY WHO DIDN'T REALIZE STUFF"
name[6] = "Mach"
name[7] = "Soap"
name[8] = "Mach"
name[9] = "Soap"
name[10] = "Mach"
name[11] = "Soap"
name[12] = "Angela"
name[13] = "Mach"
name[14] = "Chroma"
name[15] = "Mach"
name[16] = "Chroma"
name[17] = "Mach"
name[18] = "Tex"
name[19] = "Mach"
name[20] = "Tex"
name[21] = "Mach"
name[22] = "Tex (CAN'T ACTUALLY D-SMASH)"
name[23] = "Mach"
name[24] = "App"
name[25] = "Mach"
name[26] = "Soap"
name[27] = "Mach"
name[28] = "Tex"
name[29] = "Mach"
name[30] = "App"
name[31] = "Mach"
name[32] = "App"
name[33] = "Mach"
name[34] = "App"
name[35] = "Mach"
name[36] = "App"
name[37] = "Mach"
name[38] = "Angela"
name[39] = "Mach"
name[40] = "Tex"
name[41] = "Mach"
name[42] = "Angela"
name[43] = "Mach"
name[44] = "App"
name[45] = "Mach"
//As you can see, it is quite easy to add extra details for
//each message simply by adding an extra array. 
//It's that simple!

//This determines the number of pixels each line can be.
line_length = 420
//This controls the speed of the the text.
text_speed = 1
//This is the  x position in which the string starts at.
string_x = 16
//This is the y position in which the string starts at.
string_y = 48
//This determines the vertical spacing between lines.
//When set to zero, the spacing will only be the string's height.
vertical_spacing = 0
//This is the x position of the question box.
question_box_x = 32
//This is the y position of the question box.
question_box_y = 128
//This is the x position of the text drawn in relevance to question_box_x.
question_x = 18
//This is the y position of the text drawn in relevance to question_box_y.
question_y = 7
//This is the x position of the names.
name_x = 50
//This is the y position of the names.
name_y = 22
//This is the x position of the headshot.
headshot_x = 12
//This is the y position of the headshot.
headshot_y = 12
//This is the vertical spacing in between "Yes" and "No".
question_vert_spacing = 2
//This is the x postion in relevance to question_box_x.
highlight_x = 2
//If this charcter is detected, initiate a highlight.
highlight_open_character = "["
//This character determines the end of a highlight. Anything enclosed
//will be highlighted.
highlight_close_character = "]"
//If this charcter is detected, end messages.
end_character = "*"
//If this charcter is detected, ask question or jump to next position.
jump_character = "^"
//If this character is detected, initiate a manual pause.
pause_open_character = "&lt;"
//This character determines the number. The enclosed number
//is the length of the manual pause.
pause_close_character = "&gt;"


//The following variables do not need to be changed and are only used
//by the code.



//This determins if the messages end.
message_end = 0
//This determines when the typing is finished.
type_end = 0
//This determines if the meesage is a question message.
message_question = 0
//This is the target position if yes is selected.
yes_position = 0
//This is the target position if no is selected.
no_position = 0
//This is the option selected by the user.
question_selection = 1
//This detemins if the message is a jump message.
message_jump = 0
//This is the position of the next message.
jump_position = 0
//This is the string that is going to be displayed. It contains the
//modified version of the actual string.
display_string = ""
//This states the current position we are at in str[x] for adding
//characters into display_string.
position = 0
//This states the current position we are in display_string. This is
//used to prevent line breaks in the middle of a word.
display_position= 0
//This counter tells us when it's time to make a line break.
width_counter = 0
//This finds the last space.
last_space = 0
//The array index of the message that is currently being displayed.
message_display = 0
//This is used to count the number of phrases that will be highlighted.
highlight_number = 0
//This stores the starting position of the highlighted text.
highlight_position[0] = 0
//This stores the length of the highlighted text.
highlight_length[0] = 0
//This is used to count the number of manual pauses that are in the message.
pause_number = 0
//This stores the position of the manual pause.
pause_position[0] = 0
//This stores the number of steps the manual pause lasts.
pause_length[0] = 0
//This variable stores the edited message.
current_string = ""


//Gives the user a second to realize the window has opened before the text
//starts typing out.
alarm[0] = 10
</argument>
      </arguments>
    </action>
    <action id="611" library="1">
      <!--action name: Variable-->
      <kind>VARIABLE</kind>
      <allowRelative>true</allowRelative>
      <question>false</question>
      <canApplyTo>true</canApplyTo>
      <actionType>CODE</actionType>
      <functionName/>
      <relative>false</relative>
      <not>false</not>
      <appliesTo>.self</appliesTo>
      <arguments>
        <argument kind="STRING">nexted</argument>
        <argument kind="EXPRESSION">0</argument>
      </arguments>
    </action>
    <action id="201" library="1">
      <!--action name: Create_Object-->
      <kind>NORMAL</kind>
      <allowRelative>true</allowRelative>
      <question>false</question>
      <canApplyTo>true</canApplyTo>
      <actionType>FUNCTION</actionType>
      <functionName>action_create_object</functionName>
      <relative>false</relative>
      <not>false</not>
      <appliesTo>.self</appliesTo>
      <arguments>
        <argument kind="GMOBJECT">Uncontrollable</argument>
        <argument kind="EXPRESSION">0</argument>
        <argument kind="EXPRESSION">0</argument>
      </arguments>
    </action>
  </actions>
</event>
