<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<event category="CREATE" id="0">
  <actions>
    <action id="603" library="1">
      <!--action name: Code-->
      <kind>CODE</kind>
      <allowRelative>false</allowRelative>
      <question>false</question>
      <canApplyTo>true</canApplyTo>
      <actionType>CODE</actionType>
      <functionName/>
      <relative>false</relative>
      <not>false</not>
      <appliesTo>.self</appliesTo>
      <arguments>
        <argument kind="STRING">str[0] = "If you're reading this, good job getting this far. You are truly a seasoned adventurer. If you haven't run into one of those glowing things yet, you're very lucky."
str[1] = "According to [Chroma,] these glowing things are called [Sprites.] They have wings that allow them to fly through the air. However, these wings also serve as a weapon, for they are very sharp. They have a spinning attack where they will spin around and try to scratch you."
str[2] = "From what I can tell, the [Sprites] are invulnerable to almost all attacks. However, [D-Smashing] them will temporarily stun them allowing you to get a bit ahead of them before they catch up to you again."
str[3] = "However, you cannot [D-Smash] them while they are using their spin attack. That will just get yourself hurt. Note that they can only use their spin attack once in a while. After they use their spin attack, they have to take a bit of time to 'charge it up' again."
str[4] = "[Sprites] will only use their spin attack when they get close. After they use their spin attack, you have a short amount of time to [D-Smash] them before they use the spin attack again. Use this to your advantage."
str[5] = "You will almost certainly run into some [Sprites] in the path ahead. Good luck."
str[6] = "Oh yeah, I mentioned someone named [Chroma.] I should explain that real quick. Ever since I first got to [Planet Stone, Aneroid] has been communicating with me to make sure everything is going okay."
str[7] = "Recently, [Chroma] was brought to life on [Frank's Fleet] (I wrote these signs one year after [Mach] left). Ever since, [Aneroid] has had us able to communicate through messages."
str[8] = "Apparently, [Chroma] has a telekenetic link to [Frank] that allows them to communicate through thoughts for some reason. Apparently it's because [Frank] is just making sure that at least one apple will survive by making sure they're alright. Cliche, but convenient."
str[9] = "Through [Chroma,] I learned a lot of things about this planet. However, [Frank] is refusing to tell anyone what the [Sprites] are doing here. Which is odd."
str[10] = "Oh well. I shouldn't be questioning these kind of things. I shouldn't have you wasting your time reading these signs, anyways. On you go, and good luck.*"

img[0] = Sign
img[1] = Sign
img[2] = Sign
img[3] = Sign
img[4] = Sign
img[5] = Sign
img[6] = Sign
img[7] = Sign
img[8] = Sign
img[9] = Sign
img[10] = Sign

name[0] = "Sign"
name[1] = "Sign"
name[2] = "Sign"
name[3] = "Sign"
name[4] = "Sign"
name[5] = "Sign"
name[6] = "Sign"
name[7] = "Sign"
name[8] = "Sign"
name[9] = "Sign"
name[10] = "Sign"

event_inherited();
</argument>
      </arguments>
    </action>
    <action id="201" library="1">
      <!--action name: Create_Object-->
      <kind>NORMAL</kind>
      <allowRelative>true</allowRelative>
      <question>false</question>
      <canApplyTo>true</canApplyTo>
      <actionType>FUNCTION</actionType>
      <functionName>action_create_object</functionName>
      <relative>false</relative>
      <not>false</not>
      <appliesTo>.self</appliesTo>
      <arguments>
        <argument kind="GMOBJECT">Uncontrollable</argument>
        <argument kind="EXPRESSION">0</argument>
        <argument kind="EXPRESSION">0</argument>
      </arguments>
    </action>
  </actions>
</event>
