<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<event category="CREATE" id="0">
  <actions>
    <action id="603" library="1">
      <!--action name: Code-->
      <kind>CODE</kind>
      <allowRelative>false</allowRelative>
      <question>false</question>
      <canApplyTo>true</canApplyTo>
      <actionType>CODE</actionType>
      <functionName/>
      <relative>false</relative>
      <not>false</not>
      <appliesTo>.self</appliesTo>
      <arguments>
        <argument kind="STRING">//Enclosing a part of a message in square brackets [] will cause the 
//enclosed string to be highlighted.

//Placing an asterisk * at the end of a message tells the code that
//the current message is the last message.

//Putting an exponent sign ^ at the end of a message followed by a number will cause the 
//next position to be at the number. If it is followed by a number, a comma, and then another number,
//then the code will open up a box for the player to choose which path to take.
//The first number is for the yes position, and the second is for the no position.

//If you surround a number by a less than sign &lt; and a greater then sign &gt;, the code will do a manual
//pause for the  specified number of steps.

//These are the actual messages.
str[0] = "IT'S YOU!!"
str[1] = "How are you, gentlemen?&lt;30&gt; All your base are belong to us.&lt;30&gt; You are on the way to destruction."
str[2] = "What you say!"
str[3] = "You have no chance to survive make your time.&lt;30&gt; Ha ha ha ha ...."
str[4] = "All jokes aside... WHO ARE YOU?!"
str[5] = "My name is [Tex]. And who are you?"
str[6] = "Erm...&lt;30&gt; I don't know. People just call me [the Apple]. I am the holder of the [Seed of Peace]. If I find out my name from my nemesis, I can finally create world peace... but the [Evil Toaster] got away through the [Worminator]."
str[7] = "World peace from some mere seed? How the hell do you expect that to work?"
str[8] = "Well, the world's only magic blue apple told me a legend about it."
str[9] = "[Shaman]? He's a legend and his existence is merely a coincidence. This [Seed of Peace] junk is also a legend. I have proof that it doesn't exist."
str[10] = "Are you trying to dampen my confidence? You've tried to kill me twice with your funny [ARS] turrets that you built from unbreakable materials, so I wouldn't be surprised if you are."
str[11] = "Seriously, think. Why would [the Bots] put such a seed inside of you? That's completely against their intentions."
str[12] = "[The Bots]?"
str[13] = "You don't know them? You've certainly been playing into their hands this entire time. Oh well, you'll find out soon enough. Well, actually, you won't, because you'll be dead."
str[14] = "Dead? Who are you, really?! And what's with this [ARS] stuff?"
str[15] = "I am part of [ARS]. [ARS] fights viscous kitchen appliances. I was sent here to kill you."
str[16] = "What? You fight the toasters too? If [ARS] wants to fight the toasters, then why do they want to kill me?"
str[17] = "Fighting toasters? We do not take part in such silliness - we have much stronger appliances to fight. As for [ARS] wanting you dead, it was not my decision to kill you. I know you're strong, but it's for the greater good."
str[18] = "Tell me more about [ARS] and [The Bots]. What other kitchen appliances?"
str[19] = "I am sorry. I cannot tell you because your knowing may rip a hole in the space-time continuum based off of your possible actions. I time traveled here from the recent future, see?"
str[20] = "So much to take in... Now I can't go on any more adventures without my [Worminator]."
str[21] = "That's true. The [Evil Toaster] is a coward - he ran away from me. He most certainly doesn't know your name. Why can't you go and just think up a name for yourself if you ever walk away from this scene?"
str[22] = "I will walk away from this scene, that's for sure."
str[23] = "Maybe you will, but you'll find yourself becoming overconfident if you always keep up such thoughts. Now that we're at the point, let's duel... [CRAZY LU], SEND IN THE [HURTS]!*"
//These are the headshots that correspond to each message.
img[0] = RedNoAnim
img[1] = TexFace
img[2] = RedNoAnim
img[3] = TexFace
img[4] = RedNoAnim
img[5] = TexFace
img[6] = RedNoAnim
img[7] = TexFace
img[8] = RedNoAnim
img[9] = TexFace
img[10] = RedNoAnim
img[11] = TexFace
img[12] = RedNoAnim
img[13] = TexFace
img[14] = RedNoAnim
img[15] = TexFace
img[16] = RedNoAnim
img[17] = TexFace
img[18] = RedNoAnim
img[19] = TexFace
img[20] = RedNoAnim
img[21] = TexFace
img[22] = RedNoAnim
img[23] = TexFace
//These are the names of the person talking in each message.
name[0] = "The Apple"
name[1] = "CATS???"
name[2] = "The Apple"
name[3] = "CATS???"
name[4] = "The Apple"
name[5] = "Tex"
name[6] = "The Apple"
name[7] = "Tex"
name[8] = "The Apple"
name[9] = "Tex"
name[10] = "The Apple"
name[11] = "Tex"
name[12] = "The Apple"
name[13] = "Tex"
name[14] = "The Apple"
name[15] = "Tex"
name[16] = "The Apple"
name[17] = "Tex"
name[18] = "The Apple"
name[19] = "Tex"
name[20] = "The Apple"
name[21] = "Tex"
name[22] = "The Apple"
name[23] = "Tex"
//As you can see, it is quite easy to add extra details for
//each message simply by adding an extra array. 
//It's that simple!

//This determines the number of pixels each line can be.
line_length = 420
//This controls the speed of the the text.
text_speed = 1
//This is the  x position in which the string starts at.
string_x = 16
//This is the y position in which the string starts at.
string_y = 48
//This determines the vertical spacing between lines.
//When set to zero, the spacing will only be the string's height.
vertical_spacing = 0
//This is the x position of the question box.
question_box_x = 32
//This is the y position of the question box.
question_box_y = 128
//This is the x position of the text drawn in relevance to question_box_x.
question_x = 18
//This is the y position of the text drawn in relevance to question_box_y.
question_y = 7
//This is the x position of the names.
name_x = 50
//This is the y position of the names.
name_y = 22
//This is the x position of the headshot.
headshot_x = 12
//This is the y position of the headshot.
headshot_y = 12
//This is the vertical spacing in between "Yes" and "No".
question_vert_spacing = 2
//This is the x postion in relevance to question_box_x.
highlight_x = 2
//If this charcter is detected, initiate a highlight.
highlight_open_character = "["
//This character determines the end of a highlight. Anything enclosed
//will be highlighted.
highlight_close_character = "]"
//If this charcter is detected, end messages.
end_character = "*"
//If this charcter is detected, ask question or jump to next position.
jump_character = "^"
//If this character is detected, initiate a manual pause.
pause_open_character = "&lt;"
//This character determines the number. The enclosed number
//is the length of the manual pause.
pause_close_character = "&gt;"


//The following variables do not need to be changed and are only used
//by the code.



//This determins if the messages end.
message_end = 0
//This determines when the typing is finished.
type_end = 0
//This determines if the meesage is a question message.
message_question = 0
//This is the target position if yes is selected.
yes_position = 0
//This is the target position if no is selected.
no_position = 0
//This is the option selected by the user.
question_selection = 1
//This detemins if the message is a jump message.
message_jump = 0
//This is the position of the next message.
jump_position = 0
//This is the string that is going to be displayed. It contains the
//modified version of the actual string.
display_string = ""
//This states the current position we are at in str[x] for adding
//characters into display_string.
position = 0
//This states the current position we are in display_string. This is
//used to prevent line breaks in the middle of a word.
display_position= 0
//This counter tells us when it's time to make a line break.
width_counter = 0
//This finds the last space.
last_space = 0
//The array index of the message that is currently being displayed.
message_display = 0
//This is used to count the number of phrases that will be highlighted.
highlight_number = 0
//This stores the starting position of the highlighted text.
highlight_position[0] = 0
//This stores the length of the highlighted text.
highlight_length[0] = 0
//This is used to count the number of manual pauses that are in the message.
pause_number = 0
//This stores the position of the manual pause.
pause_position[0] = 0
//This stores the number of steps the manual pause lasts.
pause_length[0] = 0
//This variable stores the edited message.
current_string = ""


//Gives the user a second to realize the window has opened before the text
//starts typing out.
alarm[0] = 10
</argument>
      </arguments>
    </action>
    <action id="611" library="1">
      <!--action name: Variable-->
      <kind>VARIABLE</kind>
      <allowRelative>true</allowRelative>
      <question>false</question>
      <canApplyTo>true</canApplyTo>
      <actionType>CODE</actionType>
      <functionName/>
      <relative>false</relative>
      <not>false</not>
      <appliesTo>.self</appliesTo>
      <arguments>
        <argument kind="STRING">nexted</argument>
        <argument kind="EXPRESSION">0</argument>
      </arguments>
    </action>
    <action id="201" library="1">
      <!--action name: Create_Object-->
      <kind>NORMAL</kind>
      <allowRelative>true</allowRelative>
      <question>false</question>
      <canApplyTo>true</canApplyTo>
      <actionType>FUNCTION</actionType>
      <functionName>action_create_object</functionName>
      <relative>false</relative>
      <not>false</not>
      <appliesTo>.self</appliesTo>
      <arguments>
        <argument kind="GMOBJECT">Uncontrollable</argument>
        <argument kind="EXPRESSION">0</argument>
        <argument kind="EXPRESSION">0</argument>
      </arguments>
    </action>
  </actions>
</event>
